{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "DC supply __________ be used for the transformer.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Can",
        "b": "Connect",
        "c": "Both Can and Connect",
        "d": "None"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Current ratios are in _________ of the voltage ratio.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Direct ratio",
        "b": "Inverse ratio",
        "c": "Both",
        "d": "None"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The important characteristics of the fluid used in CB are :-",
      "answers": {
        "a": "It should have good thermal and chemical stability",
        "b": "It should have high dielectric strength and are extinguish ability",
        "c": "Non- in flammability and high thermal conductivity",
        "d": "All"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "SF6 circuit breaker is",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Expensive",
        "b": "SF6 gas has to be reconditioned after every operation of the breaker and additional equipment is required for these purposes",
        "c": "Both Expensiv and SF6 gas has to be reconditioned after every operation of the breaker and additional equipment is required for these purposes",
        "d": "None"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "A potential transformer is a",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Step up transformer",
        "b": "Step down transformer",
        "c": "Both Step up transformer and Step down transformer",
        "d": "None"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "_________ is used to make sure that an electrical circuit can be completely de-energized for service or maintenance.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Circuit breaker",
        "b": "Isolator",
        "c": "Fuse",
        "d": "None"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Isolators are __________",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Manually operated",
        "b": "Motorized",
        "c": "Both Manually operated and Motorized",
        "d": "None"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "In a transformer, if N2 is number of secondary winding N1 is the number of primary winding then, if (N2/N1) ratio is greater than 1.It is called as ________",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Step up transformer",
        "b": "Step down transformer",
        "c": "Isolation transformer",
        "d": "None"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Oil transformer usually consist of,",
      "answers": {
        "a": "A conservator tank, buchholz relay",
        "b": "Breather of dehydrating type",
        "c": "Winding temperature-indicator, oil temperature indicator",
        "d": "All"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "In case of, OFF circuit taps, the transformer must be _________ before the tap changer mechanism is operated.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Energized",
        "b": "De-energized",
        "c": "Both Energized and De-energized",
        "d": "None"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "To prevent the moisture from entering the conservator, a __________ is provided that will dry the air as the breather takes place.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Magnesium dioxide breather",
        "b": "Silica gel breather",
        "c": "Both Magnesium dioxide breather and Silica gel breather",
        "d": "None"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "In double bus'bar system ,there is a provision of a bus-bar coupling switch for transferring operation from one bus-bar to another _________ .",
      "answers": {
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": ""
    }
  ]
}
